http://www.ciachef.edu/privacy-policy/

Welcome to the Culinary Institute of America
Home >
Privacy Notice
The Culinary Institute of America (“the CIA” or “we”), a private, non-profit educational institution, presents this Privacy Notice in the interests of fairness, transparency and accountability regarding the privacy of individuals whose personal data we collect and process (“data subjects” or “you”). Our collection and processing of your personal data is lawfully based on our legitimate interests as a private, non-profit higher education institution.
The CIA understands your use of our online applications to indicate your consent to the collection, processing and use of your personal data as described in this Notice, except where we request active, express consent or where such consent is required by law.
The CIA collects and processes personal information from and about data subjects, who may be prospective students and their family members, alumni/ae, prospective donors, donors, prospective employees, employees, restaurant patrons, food enthusiasts, conference attendees, private event clients, CIA market and store customers, and other members of the public.
The CIA will not knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of thirteen without first requesting parental consent.
Our websites contain links to other sites which have their own privacy practices not under the control of the CIA. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy notices for those external sites.
How We Collect and Process Your Personal Data
A. Cookies
A text file called a “cookie” may be placed in the browser files of your computer when you visit our online applications. Although the cookie itself does not contain personal information, it provides information about your user session. A cookie file cannot read data off a hard disk or read cookie files created by other websites.
You may block the placement of cookies by changing your browser setting pertaining to cookies. This setting can also be changed to provide notification when a cookie file is placed. Our website does not require cookies to be accepted in order to function.
We understand that you consent to the placement of cookies on our website if you do not change your browser settings as described above. You may change your browser settings to block cookies at any time.
We use the Facebook Conversion Pixel, Google Analytics, Google AdWords Conversion tracker, and other services that place cookies on a browser across the website. These cookies help increase the website’s effectiveness for our visitors. These cookies are set and read by Google, Facebook, or the specific provider. We also share unique anonymous identifiers with third parties to coordinate advertising and reporting across devices and browsers. To opt out of Google and Facebook tracking, please visit
http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/ or https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217.
Any Google user data may be accessed and/or deleted via My Activity.
B. General Practices
We will not sell your personal information. We will not disclose your personal information without your permission unless a legal exception applies (for example, in case of emergency, to protect safety on campus, or in response to a valid subpoena or court order).
We retain your information for a period of time in accordance with our legitimate interests or as needed to comply with applicable law.
We may combine your personal data with device information and location information (with your consent, where required) to serve you specifically, such as to deliver a product to you according to your preferences or restrictions, or for advertising or advertising targeting purposes.
Internal CIA policy governs the use of the CIA’s network and computing resources by CIA employees, contractors and students, and also addresses privacy expectations.
C. Data You Provide Voluntarily
We may collect data about you when you provide it to us voluntarily, such as through your use of our online applications; when you contact us directly by e-mail, telephone, in person or in writing; when you order goods and services; or any other means by which you voluntarily provide personal information to us.
Types of information we collect about you may include but is not limited to: name, e-mail address, address, telephone number, payment information (for example, credit or debit card details), information about your computer (for example, your IP address and browser type), tracking information (for example, which pages you have viewed, the time you viewed them and what you clicked on), information about your mobile device (such as your geographical location), and any other information you provide when completing forms.
Financial Information
The CIA recognizes the sensitivity of personal financial information and accords it the additional strict privacy and security safeguards appropriate to the classification of sensitive/highly confidential. CIA personnel are involved in handling financial information on strictly a need-to-know basis and receive appropriate training in financial information privacy and security. The CIA does not share nonpublic financial information with nonaffiliated third parties without consent.
The CIA may collect and process personal financial information only in very limited contexts for the purposes of accepting or making payment lawfully based on its legitimate interests or in support of or preparation for an agreement. In terms of accepting payment, these purposes include: accepting charitable contributions (usually through the Advancement Office), accepting payment for goods or services (such as at a CIA restaurant), and accepting payment for student educational charges (such as tuition and board, through the Student Financial & Registration Services). We may collect financial information from the credit or debit payment card if you choose to use this method of payment; or from your personal check if you choose to use this method of payment.
In the case of CIA students or prospective students, financial information about a student and/or parents may be collected as part of the process of applying for financial aid. The CIA may collect a student’s Social Security Number only as the official identifier for state and federal financial aid documents and related processing.
The CIA also collects and processes nonpublic financial information from its employees for compensation, benefits and tax and purposes; and from independent contractors for payment and related purposes.
Electronic Communications
We offer various opportunities to subscribe to electronic communications. If you choose to subscribe, we gather your e-mail address. With your consent, we may contact you at the telephone number that you provide to us by way of direct dial calls, autodialed and prerecorded message calls, and text messages. In this manner we may send you information relating to our products and services, including confirmations and updates, receipts, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages; and/or communicate with you about contests, offers, promotions, rewards, upcoming events, and other news about products and services offered by the CIA.
You may remove yourself from any public CIA mailing list by unsubscribing on the e-mail’s subscription management page via a link at the bottom of each e-mail. You must unsubscribe from each list you wish not to receive e-mails from. More information about communicating your preferences can be found further in this Notice.
The CIA’s Office of Advancement periodically sends e-mails for the purpose of communication to persons with existing relationships with the CIA, as well as fund-raising campaigns. These e-mails will be identified as coming from the CIA’s Office of Advancement, and the CIA’s Office of Annual Giving, respectively. Recipients of these e-mails can opt out at any time by following the procedures outlined in this Notice.
Social Media
The CIA uses social media, which may allow you to connect and share your actions, comments, content, and information publicly or with friends. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public, and consider the privacy concerns of yourself and others when choosing what to share in social media.
Our social media whose privacy practices we do not control. Please contact those sites and services directly to learn about their privacy practices. Use caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.
Surveys
We occasionally conduct optional surveys. We use the data from survey responses to better target content to our audiences.
Registration Forms
We offer online registration for CIA events, such as admissions information, courses, conferences, and restaurant reservations. Registration features invite you to voluntarily provide personal information, which may include contact information (name, telephone number and/or e-mail address).
Information Request Forms
We use information request forms that invite you to voluntarily provide personal information such as names, addresses, and telephone numbers. We may send text messages to cellular telephone numbers within our database so that interested individuals can be contacted by one of our representatives. By providing a cellular telephone number, you agree to be contacted by the CIA on your cellular telephone by such means. You may change your mind and decline to be contacted in this manner by contacting us at the information below.
D. Aggregated Tracking Information
We may track your traffic patterns throughout our online applications in a de-identified manner. We do not correlate this information with identifiable data about you. We may break down overall usage statistics according to a visitor’s domain name, browser type, and Multipurpose Internet Mail Extension (MIME) type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every online application user’s browser).
We may also track and catalog some online application user data, including the search terms entered and actions taken, but this tracking information is not associated with individual online application users.
We use aggregated tracking information to determine which areas are preferred by users and to tailor our content to users’ needs.
We do not share aggregated tracking information with any third party, with the following exceptions: to a contractor engaged to conduct collection or processing for our legitimate interests; in accordance with the law or valid legal process; or to protect the personal safety of our online application users or the public.
E. Data From Third Parties
Where permitted or authorized by law, we may receive information about you from third-party databases or services that provide information about business people and companies, or from third parties from whom we have purchased information (including an individual’s name). We may combine this data with information we already have about you. This helps us to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new customers, prospective students or donors, and provide information about opportunities, products and services that may be of interest to you.
F. Use of Personal Data
We may use your personal information for the following purposes: to provide you with the opportunities, information, services, products, and functionality offered on our online applications; to fulfill your requests, including but not limited to making reservations, paying for services, joining e-mail lists, sending CIA gift cards to recipients that you designate; to communicate with you about your account or your use of our online applications, services, products and/or functionality; to respond to, or follow up on, your comments and questions; to provide customer service otherwise; to communicate with you about special offers and other marketing communications; to communicate with you about employment opportunities; to operate and improve our online applications, products, services, and functionality; to process and deliver contest entries and rewards; to authenticate your credit or debit card account information, if applicable; to personalize your experience on our online applications; in combination with other information we may get from third parties, to help understand your needs and to provide you with better service; to perform statistical analysis; to protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity; to comply with our policies, procedures and legal obligations; to support our education mission and administrative operations; and as otherwise consented to by you and as required or permitted by applicable law.
G. Communication Preferences and Opting Out
You may at any time change your preferences about which if any communications you would like to receive.
Upon receipt of an opt-out request, we will update our records as promptly as practical. Note, however, that you may receive additional communications after requesting removal while we process your request. Additionally, information may exist in multiple lists within our system, and our technology limits the processing of opt-out requests to the specific list source. For this reason, we recommend that you adjust your e-mail preferences rather than opting out completely. We will continuously assess our responsiveness to opt-out requests with respect to new technologies, business practices and our visitors’ needs.
To opt out, you may choose from the following methods:
To unsubscribe from an e-mail list:
Choose the “Remove me from future messages” link at the bottom of any CIA e-mail; or
Send an e-mail to webmaster@culinary.edu and specify which type of communication you wish to discontinue; or
Write a request to: Webmaster, The Culinary Institute of America, 1946 Campus Drive, Hyde Park, NY 12538; or
Fax a request to: 845-905-4037.
For any other privacy preferences, questions, or concerns, please contact the Director of Compliance & Information Privacy at 845-451-1429. Complaints about privacy may be made via the CIA’s confidential Hotline at 845-905-4477 or CIAHotline@culinary.edu.
H. Student Medical/Treatment/Health Information
The CIA is not a covered entity or business associate under the Health Insurance Portability and Accessibility Act (HIPAA) or the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health (HITECH) Act.
Student health information is provided to the CIA by students for public health, safety, and treatment purposes. The CIA handles student health information in strictest confidence, with respect for individual autonomy, and with appropriate safeguards for sensitive information as required by law and CIA policy.
I. Additional Notice for California Residents
California residents who provide “personal information” (as defined in the statute) in obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us, once a calendar year, information about the personal information we shared, if any, with other businesses for marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of personal information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared such personal information for the immediately prior calendar year. To obtain this information, please contact us by sending a letter or calling us at the contact information above.
J. Additional Notice for EU Data Subjects
This section applies if you are a data subject located in the European Union (EU). The EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), effective May 24, 2018, is a complex piece of legislation which may in some cases conflict with U.S., state, or other privacy laws and rules. The CIA will approach any conflict of laws on a case-by-case basis.
The CIA is the data controller for the processing of your personal data on the lawful basis of our legitimate interests in most cases, and possibly on other permitted lawful bases depending on the context of the data collection and processing, such as the contractual basis or legal obligation. The person serving in the role of data protection officer is the CIA’s Director of Compliance & Information Privacy, who can be reached at 845-451-1429; or The Culinary Institute of America, 1946 Campus Drive, Hyde Park, NY 12538 USA; or CIAHotline@culinary.edu.
Subject to the GDPR, you have the following rights in relation to your personal data:
Right of access: If you ask us, we will confirm whether we are processing your personal data and, if so, provide you with a copy of that personal data (along with certain other details). If you require additional copies, we may need to charge a reasonable fee. The CIA may use all reasonable measures to verify the identity of a data subject who requests access.
Right to rectification: If your personal data is inaccurate or incomplete, you are entitled to have it rectified or completed. The CIA will take reasonable steps to ensure that inaccurate personal data will be corrected or deleted.
Right to erasure: You may ask us to delete or remove your personal data and we will do so in some circumstances, such as where we no longer need it (we may not delete your data when other interests outweigh your right to deletion).
Right to restrict processing: You may ask us to restrict or block the processing of your personal data in certain circumstances, such as where you contest the accuracy of that personal data or object to us processing it. We will tell you before we lift any restriction on processing.
Right to data portability: You have the right to obtain your personal data from us if the processing was based on consent or for the performance of a contract. If this applies, we will give you your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. You may reuse it elsewhere.
Right to object: You may ask us at any time to stop processing your personal data, and we will do so:
If we are relying on a legitimate interest to process your personal data—unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing; or
If we are processing your Personal Data for direct marketing.
Rights in relation to automated decision-making and profiling: You have the right to be free from decisions based solely on automated processing of your personal data, including profiling, that affect you, unless such processing is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract between you and us or you provide your explicit consent to such processing.
Right to withdraw consent: If we rely on your consent as the lawful basis on which to process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. This will not affect the lawfulness of processing based on your prior consent or the lawfulness of processing that does not require consent under the GDPR.
Special categories of personal data: The CIA will process such data sensitive data from an EU data subject (for example, from a student EU data subject) only with consent and only for public health, safety, social care, or treatment purposes; to protect the vital interest of the data subject; or for another purpose permissible under the GDPR.
Right to complain: If you wish to complain about the CIA’s privacy practices under the GDPR, you may contact the EU Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) in the United Kingdom. The website at https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint offers information about how to submit a complaint.
K. Information Security
To ensure appropriate security and confidentiality of personal data, including the prevention of unauthorized access to or use of personal data and the equipment used for processing, the CIA has a comprehensive information privacy and security program which is reviewed and enhanced regularly. Nonetheless, perfect security of information provided to the CIA cannot be guaranteed. Visitors to our websites should use reasonable care in disclosing personal data online, and persons interested in communicating with the CIA may choose other means than the Internet to do so. For more information about our information privacy and security programs, please contact the Director of Compliance & Information Privacy at 845-451-1429.
Privacy Policy Updates
This privacy statement will be continuously assessed with respect to new technologies, business practices and our visitors’ changing needs. The CIA may change its privacy practices from time to time. If we make any changes, we will update this privacy notice accordingly (the date of the most recent change is displayed at the bottom of this notice).
Contacting the Website
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of the website, or your dealings with the website, you may contact:
Webmaster
The Culinary Institute of America
1946 Campus Drive
Hyde Park, NY 12538-1499webmaster@culinary.edu
Last updated on April 17, 2019
Contact Us
The Culinary Institute of America1946 Campus DriveHyde Park, NY 12538-1499
Phone: 845-452-9600 Contact an Admissions Counselor
AcademicsAssociate Degree ProgramsBaking and Pastry ArtsCulinary ArtsBachelor’s Degree ProgramsApplied Food StudiesCulinary ScienceFood Business ManagementHospitality ManagementFood Business Leadership—OnlineBachelor’s Degree Completion ProgramFood Business Management—SingaporeMaster’s Degree and Certificate ProgramsMaster’s in Food Business—OnlineMaster’s in Wine ManagementAccelerated Culinary Arts Certificate (ACAP)Concentrations and Travel ExperiencesCIA Bachelor’s Degree ConcentrationsAdvanced Concepts in Baking and PastryAdvanced Wine, Beverage, and HospitalityAsian Cuisine StudiesFarm-to-Table: Practices of a Sustainable TableIntrapreneurshipItalian CuisineJapanese CuisineLatin American CuisineMediterranean CuisineExtraordinary Travel ExperiencesChina TripCosta Rica TripFrance TripItaly TripPeru TripSpain TripTanzania TripRestaurants and InternshipsRestaurants: Learning By DoingInternship: Real, Life ExperienceCool CoursesAcademic Calendars/CatalogAdmissions & AidAccepted StudentsNew York OrientationCalifornia OrientationTexas OrientationPreparing for Your CIA EducationLiving on Campus and What to BringParents of Accepted StudentsTuition and Financial AidMeet the Enrollment TeamMessage Regarding New York Campus Reopening PlansNY Spring Accepted Students FAQsCA and TX Fall Accepted Students FAQsVirtual Accepted Student Day—New York CampusCIA Green and Gold—New York Fall StudentsCIA Main MenuCIA Green and Gold—New York Spring StudentsHigh School StudentsI’m a SeniorVisit Our CampusesWhy Study at the CIA?Student LifeTuition and Financial AidMeet the Admissions TeamHow to ApplyI’m a JuniorVisit Our CampusesWhy Study at the CIA?Student LifeTuition and Financial AidMeet the Admissions TeamHow to ApplyI’m a SophomoreVisit Our CampusesWhy Study at the CIA?Student LifeTuition and Financial AidMeet the Admissions TeamHow to ApplyTransfer StudentsCollege Credit Transfer PolicyCIA Turbo OptionBachelor’s Degree Completion ProgramVisit Our CampusesStudent LifeMeet the Admissions TeamHow to ApplyTuition and Financial AidAdult and Non-Traditional StudentsCIA Turbo OptionBachelor’s Degree Completion ProgramCollege Credit Transfer PolicyVisit Our CampusesWhy Study at the CIA?Student LifeMeet the Admissions TeamHow to ApplyTuition and Financial AidInternational StudentsInternational Students Admissions RequirementsConditional AcceptanceTuition, Grants, and Financial InformationStudent VisasEvents, Visits, and ResourcesVisit Our CampusesWhy Study at the CIA?Student LifeMeet the Admissions TeamHow to ApplyChineseKoreanSpanishVeteransGI Bill Approved Culinary SchoolVeteran Resources at the CIACIA Turbo OptionVisit Our CampusesStudent LifeHow to ApplyTuition and Financial AidVisit Us VirtuallyNew York Campus VisitsCareer Discovery DayCIA Summer ExperiencesJourney For JuniorsCulinary Academy Summer CampCalifornia Campus VisitsTexas Campus VisitsAccepted Student DayHow to ApplyHow to Apply: Associate and Bachelor’s DegreesHow to Apply: Master’s DegreesHow to Apply: ACAPStudent LifeTuition and Financial AidLearn About TuitionPaying for CollegeCIA ScholarshipsGrants, Loans, and Work-StudyEarn & LearnVeterans AidCollege CalculatorCode of ConductForms and PublicationsTutorial VideosApply for Financial AidAvoid These FAFSA ErrorsFunding Your EducationLearn About TuitionCode of ConductForms and PublicationsTutorial VideosCIA Code of ConductForms and PublicationsTutorial VideosWhy Study at the CIA?Meet the Admissions TeamFrequently Asked QuestionsOnline ResourcesCampusesCIA New YorkDegree ProgramsFood and Wine Enthusiast CoursesProfessional CoursesAdmissions and Financial AidStudent LifeResidential LifeResidence HallsMeal PlansLiving on Campus and What to BringClubs and ActivitiesStudent Groups and ClubsOn-Campus ActivitiesStudent Commons / The EggOff-Campus ActivitiesStudent Commons / The EggStudent ServicesCenter for Career and Academic AdvisingCounseling and Psychological ServicesStudent Health ServicesLibrary Learning CommonsOn-Campus EmploymentSafety and SecurityCIA AthleticsTeamsBasketballSchedule and ResultsRosterHead CoachTeam HistoryCross CountryTeam HistorySoccerSchedule and ResultsRosterHead CoachTeam HistoryTennisSchedule and ResultsRosterCoachesTeam HistoryVolleyballSchedule and ResultsRosterHead CoachTeam HistoryAthletics Staff DirectoryAthletic Facilities on CampusStudent HandbookCIA RestaurantsWeddings and Special EventsConrad N. Hilton LibraryMarriott PavilionLou’s WallCraig Claiborne BookstoreConferencesVisiting CampusVirtual TourRestaurantsTravel DirectionsAdmissions Tours and EventsVisitor Tours and EventsWhere to StayWhat to Do in the Hudson ValleyCIA CaliforniaDegree and Certificate ProgramsFood and Wine Enthusiast CoursesAdmissions and Financial AidStudent LifeHousing and Meal PlansMeal PlansResidence HallsLiving on Campus and What to BringStudent ActivitiesStudent ServicesCenter for Career and Academic AdvisingCounseling and Psychological ServicesStudent Health ServicesLearning Strategies CenterOn-Campus EmploymentSafety and SecurityStudent HandbookCIA RestaurantsWeddings and Special EventsSpice Islands® MarketplaceConferencesVisiting CampusVirtual TourRestaurantsTravel DirectionsAdmissions Tours and EventsVisitor Tours and EventsWhere to StaySt. Helena LodgingCalistoga LodgingRutherford LodgingYountville LodgingNapa LodgingCIA TexasDegree ProgramsFood and Wine Enthusiast CoursesProfessional CoursesAdmissions and Financial AidStudent LifeMeal Plan and Off-Campus HousingStudent ActivitiesStudent ServicesCenter for Career and Academic AdvisingStudent Health ServicesLearning Strategies CenterSafety and SecurityStudent HandbookCIA RestaurantsConferencesVisiting CampusVirtual TourRestaurantsTravel DirectionsAdmissions Tours and EventsVisitor Tours and EventsWhere to StayCIA SingaporeBachelor’s in Food Business ManagementApply OnlineTuition and Financial AidFacultyCampus MapAcademic Calendar/CatalogAbout CIACIA Students, Faculty, and Alumni BiosCIA StudentsCIA FacultyNew York FacultyCalifornia FacultyTexas FacultySingapore FacultyOnline Master’s FacultyCIA AlumniOur StoryCIA Leads the WayIndustry Leadership ConferencesPartnershipsGreen CampusWhy the CIA Matters in the World of FoodNews and MediaPress Release ArchiveCIA in the NewsFor the MediaPress Release ArchiveContacts and LocationsOnline Press KitShooting On LocationCulinary TourismParents NewsFresh Happenings ArticlesAdministrationAccreditation and ApprovalsNot-For-Profit CollegeDiversity at the CIASocial MediaCareers at the CIAInfo ForProspective StudentsAccepted StudentsParents and FamilesTeachers and Guidance CounselorsAlumniFood and Wine EnthusiastsProfessionalsDonorsVisitorsRestaurantsWeddings and EventsConferencesConsulting#OnlyAtCIAThe CIA DifferenceBecoming the Best of the BestCIA Leads the Way
